(Domoto Music Academy)
堂本音乐学院
(At around a quarter past three this afternoon, an explosion occurred at the Domoto Music Academy in Beika.)
今日下午3点15分左右，位于米花 市的堂本音乐学院内发生爆炸。 爆炸发生时正在该学院练习房内 练习的钢琴家连成岳彦(36岁)与 大提琴手水口洋介(36岁)当场死 亡。身负重伤的小提琴手河边奏 子(31岁)已被送往附近的医院。
(Soko Kabe. After graduating from the Tokyo University of Arts, she studied abroad in Vienna Art University, winning multiple musical awards.)
河边奏子 东都艺术大学毕业后，留学于维也纳艺术学院，多次获得各类音乐大奖。 回国后积极投身演出活动，是现今倍受瞩目的小提琴手之一。
Soko Kabe.
河边奏子
If you want to hate something, hate your own talent.
要恨就恨你自己的才华吧
Everything is for that silent night.
一切都是为了那宁静的夜晚
I am Kudo Shinichi, a high school detective.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I was at an amusement park with Ran, my childhood friend,
一次我和青梅竹马的同学毛利兰去游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed men in black in the process of a suspicious transaction.
目击了一群黑衣男子在进行可疑交易的现场
While caught up in watching the deal,
由于我太过于关注交易
I failed to notice that his partner had come up from behind me.
没注意到另一个同伙从我身后靠近
I was forced by that man to take in the poison.
我被那人强行灌下了毒药
When I woke up,
当我醒来后
I found that my body had shrunk.
身体竟然变小了
If they know that Kudo Shinichi is still alive,
要是被他们知道工藤新一还活着
they'll try to kill me and even my family and friends.
肯定性命不保 而且会危及到身边的人
So I listened to Professor Agasa's advice and hid my true identity.
在阿笠博士的建议下我决定隐藏自己的真实身份
When Ran asked about my name,
当小兰问起我名字时 我急中生智
the name Conan Edogawa suddenly hit me.
称自己为江户川柯南
In order to get more information about the Black Organization,
为了搜集那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran, whose father is a detective.
便寄住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家里
I'm gonna kick it, Mitsuhiko!
我要开球喽 光彦
Leave it to me!
交给我吧
Got it.
看球
Mitsuhiko!
光彦
Conan!
柯南
It's heading toward you, Ayumi!
到你那儿去啦 步美
Me?
我？
I got this!
看我的
Nice!
漂亮
They are my classmates, Genta, Ayumi and Mitsuhiko.
他们就是我现在的同学元太 步美 光彦
They founded the Detective Boys and forced me to join them.
成立了少年侦探团 还硬把我拉入伙
We have another member,
成员还有一个
Ai Haibara.
她叫灰原哀
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
真名宫野志保
Her parents, who died when she was a little girl, were both scientists in the Black Organization.
在她年幼时去世的父母曾是黑衣组织所属的科学家
She used to work for that organization too, with a code name Sherry.
她代号雪莉 曾为那伙人效力
The poison APTX 4869 was created by her.
那个APTX4869就是她开发的
However, because her only sister, Akemi Miyano,
但是 因为唯一的亲姐姐宫野明美
was killed by the people of the Black Organization. So she started to disobey the organization.
被他们杀害 开始反抗组织
She took the pill intending to end her life.
本想就此了结性命的她吞下了那粒药丸
However, her body shrunk.
身体却变小了
That's how we met and went to the same class of grade one.
就这样我们相遇了 一起读小学一年级
In the meantime, I am still investigating the true identity of the members of the Black Organization.
同时还在追踪那伙人的真实身份
However, this little detective
不过这个小小侦探先生呢
always forgets his own situation.
一不留神就忘了自己的处境
With his natural ability of deduction and Professor Agasa's inventions,
凭借与生俱来的推理能力和阿笠博士的发明
he has solved a lot of tricky cases.
破了一件又一件的棘手案件
Thanks to him, I am always worried.
托他的福 让我时常担惊受怕
However, when we are in the music class,
不过 在音乐课上
he got me worried for another reason.
又是另一种含义的提心吊胆了
It's your turn to speak your classic lines.
该你了 每次都说的那个
Though my body had shrunk, my mind is still clever.
身体虽然变小 头脑依旧灵活
I'm the famous detective who can solve all the cases.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
Kazuki Domoto?
堂本一挥？
You know him, right?
新一你应该知道吧
Yeah, isn't he the founder of the music academy where a bombing occurred last week?
不就是上个星期发生爆炸的音乐学院的创始人吗
Actually, I am at that place right now.
话说回来 我现在就在这儿
Mr. Domoto used to be a famous pianist,
堂本先生本来是个有名的钢琴家
but he turned to play the organ all of a sudden.
突然改弹管风琴了
Plus, in order to build a new concert hall,
而且为了建一个新的音乐厅
he even brought in the organ from an old church in Germany.
把德国老教堂的管风琴都给搬来了
The one which was said to be played by Bach himself, right?
就是传说巴赫弹过的那架吧
I got the chance to attend the opening concert of Domoto hall after it's completion.
我可以去看堂本音乐厅落成后举办的首场音乐会哦
I even get to watch the rehearsal.
还能去看彩排呢
It's all arranged by Sonoko.
都是园子安排的
Come to think of it, Domoto Concert Hall was built by Suzuki Construction Company.
说起来 堂本音乐厅还是铃木建筑公司建造的呢
A piano key?
钢琴的琴键？
It flew over here?
竟然飞到这儿来了
Why don't you come with, Shinichi?
一起去吧 新一
You'll get to hear a Stradivarius played live.
能在现场听斯特拉迪瓦里呢
Didn't you always say that you want to hear one yourself someday?
你以前不总是说想听听真正的小提琴吗
What's that guy doing?
那人是怎么回事啊
Hey, are you listening, Shinichi?
喂 你有在听吗 新一
Sorry, sorry.
对不起 对不起
Unfortunately! I'm in the middle of an investigation now.
真不凑巧 现在正忙着查案呢
Can't you take some time off?
一点时间也抽不出吗
The rehearsal is on the day after tomorrow.
彩排在后天
Sorry, I can't go.
不好意思 我还是不去了
The concert is next Tuesday.
音乐会在下周二
I really can't make it.
真的不行啦
I said I was working on a case...
不是说了正在查案…
But you might be done with the case by then.
说不定到时候已经结案了啊
I'll ask Sonoko to reserve a seat for you.
反正我拜托园子给你也留了个座位
I told you I couldn't go. Stop being so meddlesome.
不是说了不用了吗 真是多管闲事
Meddlesome?
多管闲事？
No...
不是…
You are right!
说得没错
I'm just a meddlesome karate fool.
反正我就是个爱管闲事的空手道傻子
That's not what I said.
话不是这么说的啦
It doesn't matter. Even if you listened to a real Stradivari,
没关系 反正就算听了斯特拉迪瓦里
you still can't become the real Holmes.
你也变不成福尔摩斯
What?
什么
Because you are tone-deaf, Shinichi.
因为新一你是个音痴
Ran, you little!
兰 你这家伙
Well, keep up the good work, famous tone-deaf detective.
那么 尽量努力吧 音痴的名侦探
Puff, I'll never invite that deduction geek again!
真是的 以后再也不约那推理狂了
Seriously.
真是的
Hello.
喂
Conan, what do you want to eat tonight?
柯南啊 今晚想吃什么
Well...
那个…
How about curry? Or do you want to eat something else?
咖喱怎么样 还是换点别的？
Curry sounds fine.
咖喱就行
Great, you've done me a great favor by being so honest.
太好了 你这么坦率真是帮了我大忙了
Stay safe and come back home before it gets dark, okay?
那要注意安全 天黑前要回家哦
Okay.
好
See you.
再见
When I am Conan, I'm being "honest", huh?
作为柯南的话就能坦率了
(Kazuki Domoto Organist and Composer)
堂本一挥 管风琴演奏家•作曲家
Bravo! Very well played!!
精彩!　太完美了!!
That was excellent, Mr. Domoto.
弹得太好了 堂本先生
The Organ has a different kind of charm from the piano.
和钢琴相比别有一番魅力呢
No wonder Kazuki Domoto is a well-known performer. That was a marvelous performance.
真不愧是堂本一挥 演奏得真是精彩绝伦
I've seen that man on television.
那个人我在电视上看到过
There, the man with glasses.
看 就是那个戴眼镜的人
That's Mr. Takumi Fuwa.
那是谱和匠先生
(Takumi Fuwa  Domoto Hall director) He's been the sole tuner for Mr. Domoto for 35 years.
35年来一直是堂本先生的专属调律师 谱和 匠 堂本音乐厅馆长
He's now the director of Domoto Hall.
这次当上了堂本音乐厅的馆长了呢
That guy...
那个人…
The man who just turned his head is a German, Mr. Hans Muller.
刚刚回头的德国人是汉斯•谬勒先生
He's a tuner of pipe organs.
管风琴的调律师
(Hans Muller  Organ Tuner) Though he looks pretty happy now
别看他现在笑得挺开心 汉斯•谬勒 管风琴调律师
I heard he had frequent disputes with Mr. Domoto in the past.
听说起初经常和堂本先生发生争执
The one interpreting next to him is Mr. Domoto's son,
旁边那个正在翻译的是堂本先生的儿子
(Genya Domoto  Pianist, Kazuki Domoto's son) Mr. Genya Domoto, a pianist.
钢琴家弦也先生 堂本弦也 钢琴演奏家•堂本一挥之子
He's also in charge of the upcoming performance.
是这次演出的负责人
Also, the two women over there.
还有 那边那两个女的
They are both Mr. Domoto's students.
她们都是堂本先生的徒弟
The one on the right is Miss Rara Chigusa, a soprano,
右边那个是堂本音乐学院第9届学生
(Rara Chigusa  Soprano Singer) from the class of 9 in Domoto Music Academy.
女高音歌手 千草拉拉小姐 千草拉拉 女高音歌手
The woman who seems a bit psychotic is
旁边那个看上去有点神经质的人
a student from class of 8 in the same academy.
是同一所学院的第8届学生
(Shion Yamane  Violinist) A violinist, Ms. Shion Yamane.
小提琴手 山根紫音小姐 山根紫音 小提琴演奏家
She's substituting for Soko Kabe, the person who got injured in the explosion then?
是那个在爆炸事故中受伤的河边奏子的候补吧
Yes, that's right.
对 对
When the accident happened,
事故发生时
the Miss Kabe's Stradivarius just so happened to be sent for adjustments,
凑巧河边奏子的斯特拉迪瓦里送出去调整
so it wasn't destroyed.
躲过了一劫
So Miss Shion borrowed it for the performance.
紫音小姐就把它借了过来演奏
And the person who's sitting in the front is...
然后 坐在观众席最前面是
She's Miss Reiko Akiba, isn't it? The soprano singer.
是秋庭怜子小姐吧 那个女高音歌手
I knew you would know her.
这个应该知道才对
She is very famous.
因为她可是个名人啊
(Reiko Akiba  Soprano Singer)
秋庭怜子 女高音歌手
Now, Miss Shion, get ready.
那么 紫音 准备一下
Okay.
好的
Let's begin with the first piece, Ave Maria.
从第一首《圣母颂》开始
Yes.
好
Looking at it, it seems you are not ready to rehearse with me, right?
看这样子 你还没法和我配合吧
I'm sorry. You'll have to wait for a little longer.
不好意思 你再等等
I'm, I'm sorry.
对 对不起
We could finally hear a Stradivari in person, Officer Sato.
终于能到听现场版的斯特拉迪瓦里了呢 佐藤刑警
Personally, I prefer an Amati.
我个人还是比较喜欢阿玛蒂
Be quiet!
你们安静点
That won't do, that won't do!
不行啊不行
You are not in the moment!
一点都不在状态
What have you been doing for the past week?
这一个星期都干什么去了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Was there something wrong?
有什么不对吗
It sounded perfect.
听上去很完美嘛
No, that's not the sound which a Stradivari should make.
不 她并没有演奏出斯特拉迪瓦里应有的音色
Let's start from the top.
从头再来一次
Yes.
是
What? What happened?
怎么了 出什么事了
The string seems to have snapped.
好像是小提琴的弦断了
Sorry, I'll go change it.
对不起 我马上去换
What do you think of the balance of the sound?
声音的平衡感如何？
Well, I think it's good.
嗯 我看没问题
My, my,
哎呀呀
do I even have a chance to sing today?
今天还能不能唱啊
Miss Akiba, do you have a moment?
秋庭小姐 能不能占用点时间
Would you at least let me go to the restroom?
好歹让我上个洗手间吧
Mouri.
毛利老弟
Do you have any leads on the culprit behind the bombing?
爆炸事件的犯人 有眉目了吗
Not yet.
目前还没
The bomber used plastic explosive, right?
用的果然是塑胶炸弹吧
The timer was also found.
定时器也找到了
The bomb was set to explode at the time when the two victims were performing.
时间正好设定在两人演奏的时候
If that's the case, then...
这么说的话 果然是…
I'm sorry, Mouri,
不好意思 毛利老弟
I can't tell you the details of the investigation here and now.
现在不能对你透露调查进行的状况
Especially in front of the kids.
特别是在小孩子面前
Kids?
小孩子？
Go play with the others!
你给我过去和小鬼头们一边玩去
Yes, sir.
遵命
It's so big.
好大呀
Not only is it big, it's also beautiful.
不仅大 还这么漂亮
It's splendid, isn't it?
厉害吧
How does an organ make sound?
管风琴为什么会响啊
The principle behind it is the same as the recorders you play at school.
发声的原理和你们在学校吹的竖笛一样
See, there are lots of pipes lined up, right?
你们看 那儿不是排着很多管子吗
Just like blowing into a recorder, when we push air into the pipes,
就像吹竖笛一样将空气灌入每一根管子内
the organ will make a sound.
就会响了
Air?
空气 吗
I see.
这样啊
But the pipes don't have any holes like a recorder.
但是那些管子上没有像竖笛那样的孔啊
That's right. When we play the recorder, we use our fingers to cover the holes,
对 竖笛是用手指摁住孔
in order to make sounds of different pitches.
发出不同高度的声音
As for the organ,
而管风琴呢
we only need to press on the key to let the corresponding pipe make sound.
按下琴键 与之相对应的管子就会发出声音
Each pipe can only make one sound.
每根管子只能发出一种声音
What are those switch-like things?
那个看上去像开关的是什么
These? These are known as "Stops".
这个吗 这叫音栓
When you pull these out, the organ will make different sounds.
抽出这个的话 就可以发出各种不同的音色
For example, if I pull this out.
比如说 把这个拉出来的话
It's a trumpet!
是小号
A flute!
是长笛
An organ player should be able to combine all those sounds
管风琴演奏者把这些进行组合
to add variety to their performance.
就可以使演奏变化多端
I see. I've learned a lot today.
原来如此 长见识了
Now, time for the long-awaited quiz!
那么现在 出一道大家久等的谜题
No one is waiting for that.
哪有人久等
An opera singer who injured his throat was waiting for an operation.
一位歌剧演员弄伤了喉咙 本来等着做手术
However, he decided against the operation and got better after taking a pill from an old man.
但是他放弃了手术 用老爷爷的药丸把病治好了
Which of the following singer am I talking about?
那么这位歌剧演员是下面的哪一位呢
1. Soprano
1. 女高音（ソプラノ soprano）
2. Alto
2. 女低音（アルト alto）
3. Tenor
3. 男高音（テノール tenor）
4. Bass
4. 男低音（バス bass）
This one's difficult...
这回很难啊
Professor, how about a hint?
博士 有提示吗
How do you say "operation" in English?
“手术”用英语怎么说呢
Operation.
Operation（オペレーション）
Normally, we pronounce it as Ope.
一般念做“オペ”
Also, the pills came from an old man, right?
还有 老爷爷的药丸对吧
Conan, have you figured it out?
柯南知道了吗
It's simple.
很简单
First...
首先…
It's the first one.
第一个
The answer is the first one: Soprano.
答案是第一个 女高音
An opera singer gave up the operation,
歌剧演员（オペラ歌手）放弃了手术（オペ）
so we should remove "ope" from "opera".
从“オペラ”中去掉“オペ”
A pill is usually small and round.
药丸是指又小又圆的药
An old man's pills indicates grandpa's small circle.
老爷爷的药丸是指祖父（そふ）的小圆圈
If  we combine it with the "ra" from before,
和刚才的“ラ”组合起来
Ra...
ラ…
(Note: そふ's katakana is ソフ. The small circle is the half-voiced symbol.) The little circle...
注：“そふ”的片假名为“ソフ”，小圆圈是半浊音符号 “そふ”的
of grandpa...
小圆圈
It's soprano!
是女高音（ソプラノ soprano）
That's so boring.
无聊
You got it right, but it's still rude of you to call it a boring riddle.
答是答对了 说我无聊真是没礼貌
Excuse me, Miss Akiba, can we have a talk now?
不好意思 秋庭小姐 你看是不是可以谈谈了
Geez. It won't take long, will it?
受不了 不会耽误很久吧
We just need to know the details about
我们想再了解一下
the email which Miss Soko Kabe sent to you before the explosion.
爆炸前河边奏子给你发的邮件一事
"I can't work with a bunch of amateurs who can't tell the differences in sound."
“跟一群不懂声音的差异的外行人 无法共事”
What does that mean?
这封邮件是什么意思
The meaning? It's just like what it says.
意思？不就是字面意思吗
I've told you, me and Miss Kabe...
之前我也说过 我和河边小姐…
The first time you two met was on the press conference for this public concert, right?
这次公演的记者见面会是第一次见面 没错吧
She said she was going to listen to the performance of the two who passed away
那时 她说要去听现已身亡的那两个人的演奏
and that she would email me her thoughts.
还说要把感想发邮件告诉我
Which means, the music which those two people played wouldn't match Mr. Kabe's style.
也就是说 这两人演奏的声音和河边小姐演奏的声音不同
The two called themselves musicians but they couldn't tell the difference between sound.
这两个人身为音乐家却不懂得表达声音的区别
So, Miss Kabe thought that they were not qualified to perform with her, right?
河边小姐觉得不能和他们同台演出 是吗
I think so.
我觉得是这样的
Why didn't you ask her directly?
怎么不去问她本人
Hasn't she already regained consciousness?
不是说恢复意识了吗
She is conscious, but perhaps due to the blast from the explosion
虽然恢复了意识 可能是受爆炸的冲击
she had lost her memory of the incident.
失去了事故前后的记忆
Is that so?
是吗
Also, we found this at the scene.
另外 这个掉在了现场
The body of the flute?
长笛的笛身？
Yes.
正是
(A flute consists of three parts: the mouthpiece, the body, and the foot. Only the body was left there.)
由笛头 笛身 笛尾三部分组成的长笛的笛身部分
Perhaps some student dropped it there.
有可能是某个学生掉在那里的
But isn't it suspicious that only the body was left there?
那样的话 只有笛身这点太可疑了
Does anything come to mind?
有想到什么吗
Miss Akiba?
秋庭小姐
No, nothing.
不 没有
I've had enough!
已经问够了吧
Wait, Miss Akiba!
等等 秋庭小姐
What is that?
那是什么呀
What are you drinking?
你喝的什么呀
Tea.
茶
Can I have some?
也让我喝点嘛
No.
不行
So stingy.
小气鬼
Does it contain ingredients which are beneficial for the throat?
是不是里边有对喉咙有益的成分
It's none of your business.
和你们没关系吧
If you are right,
要真是这样的话
maybe we can win the first prize in the singing competition after drinking this.
喝了这个说不定就能在合唱大赛上得第一了
Singing competition?
合唱大赛？
There will be a singing contest between the classes next week.
下次有个班级之间的合唱大赛
I know! Why don't you coach us for the competition?
对了 能不能指导一下我们的合唱啊
We'll practice in the music room at school from 2 p.m. the day after tomorrow.
后天下午两点开始要在学校的音乐教室练习
Though Miss. Ran will play the piano for us...
虽然小兰姐姐会帮我们弹钢琴
The person who will teach us singing is the problem.
但教我们唱歌的家伙有点问题
Hey, you brats!
喂 你们这群小鬼
Who did you say was the problem?
说谁有问题呢
- Seriously! What problem? - Sorry, please don't mind them.
真是的 你觉得我什么地方有问题 -对不起 你别介意
The song you picked isn't "The Ninth", is it?
你们合唱的该不会是“第九”（第九：だいく）吧
I hate that song.
我很讨厌那首
No, it's not the carpenter's song.
才不是木匠（大工：だいく）的歌呢
It's the school anthem of Teitan Primary School.
是帝丹小学的校歌哦
"The ninth" refers to Beethoven's Ninth Symphony.
“第九”是指贝多芬的《第九交响曲》
Is that so?
是这样啊
Fine, I'll coach you guys.
好吧 我给你们当合唱指导
Think of this as a favor from a Teitan Primary School alumnus.
看在同是帝丹小学校友的份上
You graduated from Teitan Primary School too?
你也是帝丹小学毕业的吗
So, please leave now. You are interfering with the rehearsal.
所以 这次你们先回去吧 碍手碍脚的
Okay.
是
I'm glad that she could coach us singing,
虽然很高兴她同意指导我们合唱 但是…
but that lady is kind of rude.
感觉很不爽呢 那个大婶
Yeah, I feel the same.
嗯 有点
She give off the stereotypical queen aura.
典型的女王陛下的感觉
She's a little like you, Haibara.
和灰原你有点像
No, I mean she's a pretty woman.
不 我是说她也是个美女
I can't tell if Miss Akiba was trying to be difficult or kind.
真搞不懂秋庭小姐是刁难人还是亲切呢
Maybe she drove everyone out to
但是说不定是为了很紧张的紫音小姐着想
take pressure off Miss Shion who seemed very nervous.
才把大家赶了出来
Aren't you reading too much into it?
是不是想太多啦
Maybe.
也许吧
0:30
0:30
You are taking it so serious against an amateur.
对于外行人别这么认真啊
A lion will go all out even if it's chasing after a rabbit.
狮子即使在追赶兔子的时候也会竭尽全力的
All right, all right, I am the rabbit.
是是 反正我是兔子啦
By the way, we should play mixed doubles next time.
对啦 下次打混双吧
We can ask Makoto and Shinichi out.
把阿真和新一叫来
Shinichi...
新一…
That deduction geek!
这个推理狂
No way.
不是吧
So, you and Shinichi got into a fight.
什么啊 原来和新一吵架啦
Marital quarrels and southern winds subside at night.
“夫妻吵架狗不理”
That's not what happened.
才不是那么回事
You two are always like this.
可是你们总是这样的呢
You get into a fight, and then always make up right away afterwards.
经常一会儿吵架一会儿又和好了
But I remember the time when you two got into a big fight.
可是那次还真是很长呢
You two didn't talk to each other for a week, right?
有一个星期左右没说话吧
When was that?
什么时候的事
Remember, during the start of the second year of middle school.
好好想想 就是刚升到初二的时候
I remember!
想起来了
At that time...
那个时候啊
Wait, what were we fighting about?
哎呀 是为了什么吵架的来着
Then, how did you two work it out?
那是怎么和好的呢
You forgot everything?
什么都忘记了啊
I think it was...
不过记得应该是…
Stop, stop, wait!
Stop Stop 等一下
Why did you two go back home together when you were having a fight?
吵架期间怎么还一起回家啊
Because our homes were in the same direction.
因为家在同一个方向嘛
Fine, just continue.
算了 继续吧
At that time, it was someone singing.
那个时候 是歌声
We heard someone singing from the river.
那个时候 从河边传来了歌声
While we were listening, we just...
听着听着 不知怎么的就…
made up with each other.
和好了啊
Then, what song was it?
那 是什么歌啊
What was it?
是什么来着
Well, it's a very famous song.
哎呀 记得是首很有名的曲子呢
But, how do I describe it?
可是 怎么说呢
It was a song that reached into our hearts.
是首渗透心扉的歌
♪ On the green mountain ♪
绿意盎然的山丘
♪ we hear echoes from far away ♪
传来遥远的回音
♪ We sing with smile faces ♪
唱着歌带着笑容
♪ and engrave the bright sunshine ♪
将耀眼的阳光
♪ in our heart ♪
刻印在心田
♪ We seize the future ♪
紧紧抓住未来
♪ Teitan, Teitan, Teitan Primary School ♪
帝丹　帝丹　帝丹小学啊
What do you think of their singing?
怎么样啊 孩子们的歌
Fine.
好吧
First, you,
首先 是你
your voice is too loud.
声音太大了
You have to fit in with everybody else voices.
要再多配合大家的声音
The boy with freckles.
还有旁边的雀斑小子
Your pitch is right, but sometimes your mind would drift.
虽然你的音程对了 但有时会走神
Could it be because you keep staring at the face of the girl in front of you?
是在盯着前面的女孩的侧脸吧
The girl in front of you...
你前面的…
That's Haibara!
不就是灰原嘛
Next, this girl.
接着 是这个女生
You sing very well,
虽然歌唱得不错
but you should sing more like a child.
但要唱得再像小孩子一点
That's because I'm not a child.
因为我不是小孩
Your pitch was accurate and your voice was lively. Well done.
你的音程又准又有精神 非常不错
Don't be influenced by the voice beside you.
你不要被周围的声音影响
- You have to be confident. - No wonder she's a famous singer.
要有自信 -到底是歌唱家啊
Even without listening properly,
看上去没有仔细听
she could tell the everyone's voices apart.
但却能把大家的声音都清楚地分辨出来
She has the ears of a musician.
这就是音乐家的耳朵吧
The problem is
问题就是
you!
你
Yes.
是
You were completely off key the whole time!
从头到尾都没在调上
Did you do it on purpose?
应该不是故意的吧
No...
不是…
He didn't do it on purpose!
不是故意的
He's just tone deaf!
柯南只不过是音痴而已
Are you really trying to help me?
这根本就不是在帮忙
Worst of all, the piano also sounded weird.
糟糕得很 连钢琴也很奇怪
The sound was flat the whole time.
整体音阶都低了
Was the piano even tuned?
是不是没有好好调过音啊
Really?
真的吗
I didn't notice.
都没注意过呢
I think so too.
我也这样觉得
This person...
这个人…
Miss Akiba,
秋庭小姐
do you have perfect pitch?
难道你拥有绝对音感？
Yeah, I do.
嗯 有啊
What's perfect pitch?
绝对音感是什么
The ability to name the pitch
听到一个音的瞬间
upon hearing it. In other words, the ability to hear the pitch.
就能说出这个音的音名 也就是能听出音高的能力
For example.
比如
E5 mi.
E5的mi
B3 and F5, si and fa.
B3和F5的si和fa
Correct.
答对了
Awesome!
太厉害了
That's why you are a great singer.
所以唱歌才会那么棒啊
How do I put it,
怎么说呢
I don't know if it's essential for a musician to have perfect pitch.
我也不知道绝对音感对音乐家来说是不是必备的
I was born with it,
我好像是天生就是这样
but there are people that could get it after training.
但经过后天训练也是可以达到的
I heard that was the case for the former piano tuner Mr. Takumi.
听说前钢琴调律师的谱和先生就是这样的
All right, that's all my advice.
好了 我的建议就这些
You have to practice on your own next.
接下来自己好好练习啊
When you can sing better,
等你们唱得更好一些的话
I'll come back to coach you.
再来指导你们
Are you going already?
回去了吗
I'd like to hear a demonstration before you leave.
回去之前想听听您的示范呢
I agree!
赞成
How much can you pay me?
你们能付我多少钱
Professionals don't sing without being paid.
专家是没有钱就不会唱的
Goodbye.
再见
That's it.
就是这个
Hey, that's my tea.
喂 那个是我的茶
Thanks for the tea.
不客气啦
What's wrong, Genta?
怎么了 元太
What's wrong?
怎么了
Genta, Genta!
元太 元太
Are you all right, Genta?
你没事吧元太
Someone added something in it.
有人在里面下了什么东西
That's what you're thinking, right?
你也这么想吧
How could that happen?
不会吧
How's that possible?
怎么可能
Anyway, let's take him to the hospital first.
总之 先带他去医院
Is Genta going to be all right?
不要紧的吧元太
He seemed to be in a lot of pain just now.
好像相当痛苦的样子啊
His eyes even turned red.
眼睛都红了
When was the last time you had the tea?
最后喝那个茶是在什么时候
I think it was before noon.
好像是中午之前吧
Where did you drink it?
地点呢
At the Domoto Music Academy.
在堂本音乐学院
I borrowed a classroom to practice singing.
借了教室来练习演唱
Before I left, I went to the restroom.
回去之前去了厕所
During that time, I left this bottle in the classroom
这期间这个杯子和其他行李一起
along with my other things.
放在教室了
If someone put something in it,
如果是有人放了什么东西进去的话
it had to be at that time.
就是那个时候吧
But, who could it be?
但是 究竟是谁呢
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Genta!
元太
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Not at all.
要紧的
What did the doctor say?
医生怎么说
The doctor said his throat is quite inflamed,
医生说虽然喉咙发炎很严重
but he'll recover in four or five days.
不出四五天就会好的
So you will recover?
会好的啊
That's great!
太好了
However, that means he can't speak properly for the next four days.
但是 反过来说 要四天不能发出声音呢
There are only three days until the concert at Domoto Hall.
离堂本音乐厅的公演还有三天
If Miss Reiko had drank from it,
如果被怜子小姐喝了
she might have been unable to perform.
就不能演出了
Let's call Inspector Megure
联系下目暮警部
and ask him to analyze the contents of that bottle.
让他去调查一下杯子里面的东西吧
I'll send the bottle to him then.
那我送过去吧
But before that...
可是在此之前
We'll send Genta back home.
元太的话 我们来送
I'll go too.
我也去
I need to see this child's parents
我要和这个孩子的家长见见面
and ask them why their kid drinks things from others bottle without permission.
问问他们是怎么教育出擅自喝别人东西的小孩的
I'm sorry.
对不起
Genta.
元太
Cheer up, Genta.
打起精神嘛 元太
Four days
四天时间
will pass in the blink of an eye.
一眨眼就过去了
I want... to eat... the grandpa's pills.
我想 吃 老爷爷的 药丸
The professor's riddle came true.
真的成了博士的迷题了
Everyone, move to the side.
大家 靠边让一下
No,
不对
run!
快跑
Hurry up!
快点
Damn it, I can't see his face!
可恶 看不见脸
Turn right! Turn right!
向右 向右转
What the?
怎么了
Are you OK?
没事吧
Shoot!
可恶
Are you Okay?
你不要紧吧
What's wrong with that truck?
怎么回事啊那辆卡车
Going the opposite direction on a one-way street!
在单行道上逆行
Miss Reiko,
怜子老师
your leg is bleeding.
腿上出血了
That's just a minor injury.
这点伤没事的
Did the truck stop because the taxi showed up?
是因为出租车开过来了所以才停止袭击的吗
Or was it...
还是…
Sorry, please take care of these kids.
那么 不好意思 这些孩子就拜托你们了
I'm going home in this taxi.
我就乘这辆出租车回去了
Please tell the police what just happened.
刚刚的事情跟警察说一下
You are leaving?
回去了吗
Nothing good happens when I am with you guys.
和你们在一起就没什么好事
How could she say that?
居然这么说
That's mean.
太过分了
Inspector!
警部
What's the cause of the explosion?
爆炸的原因是什么
Yes, sir.
是
We've determined that the room was filled with propane that leaked.
屋内充满了泄漏出的丙烷气体
And was ultimately detonated by the lighting of a match.
被火柴的火引爆了
However, the gas detection device was damaged before.
但是燃气自检器有事先被破坏的痕迹
That means it wasn't an accident, but a murder.
那么就不是事故 是谋杀
The victim is Osamu Shida, the owner of this shop. He's 36 years old.
死者是这家店的店主志田治先生 36岁
Mr. Shida is a violinist,
志田先生是小提琴手
a student from the class of 1 in Domoto Music Academy.
堂本音乐学院的第1届学生
The class of 1?
第1届学生？
The same as the two victims who died in the explosion.
和之前的爆炸事件的两名受害者一样啊
I don't think it's a coincidence.
我不认为是巧合哦
It's not.
不是巧合
Officer Sato.
佐藤刑警
I found this in the shop.
在店里发现了这个
That's...
这个是…
the footpiece of a flute.
长笛的笛尾
I'm sure of it.
不会错的
This is a serial homicide committed by the same culprit.
是同一个犯人的连续谋杀案
Also, the criminal left us a message.
而且罪犯留下了信息
The body and the footpiece of the flute.
笛身和笛尾
Only the mouthpiece hasn't shown up yet.
还剩下笛头
The criminal will surely commit another murder.
犯人还打算犯下一起事件
About the victim who plunged to his death in the open sea yesterday, Hisao Sone...
关于昨天在滑翔机飞行中坠落后溺水身亡的曾根久男
He seems to have been a viola player...
好像是个中提琴手
Actually, we found out that he was a student from the class of 1 in Domoto Music Academy.
事实上已经查明是堂本音乐学院的第1届学生
So, is it possible that...
那么说来 难道…
Mr. Renjo and Mr. Mizumi who died last week
和上周去世的水口先生和连城先生
and Mr. Shida who died in the explosion, were classmates.
还有前天被炸死的志田先生是同届生
Also, two years ago, the four of them formed a piano quartet.
而且两年前这四人还组过钢琴四重奏
As I thought, our suspect is a serial killer.
果然是同一犯人的连续谋杀
It should be.
应该没错
According to the prefectural police, there are
根据县警所说 布制的机翼
minute cuts by a knife on the glider wing.
也就是伞翼上有用刀刃划出的细小裂缝
What's more important is the thing we found under Mr. Sone's car seat.
更重要的是从曾根先生车子的座位下面
You found the rest part of the flute, the mouthpiece, right?
发现了长笛剩下的部分 笛头吧
Now that all the parts of the flute appeared,
但是长笛的部件集齐了
does it mean the murder will stop?
也就意味着连续谋杀案就此结束了吗
I hope so.
但愿如此啊
By the way, Ran,
对了 小兰
Yes.
是
Inside the bottle which you brought here...
小兰拿来的那个保温杯的内容物
It was determined
鉴定的结果是
there were traces of a highly irritated drug.
被混入了高刺激性的药物
It's too serious to be passed off as a prank.
如果说是恶作剧的话 有点过头了
What about the trunk which chased after us?
那个袭击我们的卡车呢
It was stolen at a place nearby the crime scene.
是现场附近被偷的车辆
Which means,
也就是说
the criminal wanted to hurt Miss Akiba
犯人想用混入保温杯里的药物
with the drug in the bottle, but failed.
弄伤秋庭小姐 结果失败
Then, he went to his next plan, which was stealing a truck and running her over.
于是采取第二步 偷了卡车袭击她
All to achieve his original purpose.
想达成他之前的目的
And the purpose is stop Miss Akiba from
就是使秋庭小姐无法参加堂本音乐厅的首次公演
performing at the Domoto Hall's opening.
就是这个目的
So, if Miss Reiko couldn't perform,
那么 怜子小姐如果无法出演公演的话
who will replace her?
会是谁来顶替呢
Most likely, Miss Rara Chigusa.
恐怕是千草拉拉吧
She was the top candidate for the soprano
本来她是女高音的第一候选人
because she's the student from the class of 9 in Domoto Music Academy and was taught by Mr. Domoto.
她是堂本音乐学院第9届的堂本先生的学生
However, at that time,
可是这个时候
Miss Soko Kabe who was chosen to give the performance
就因为已经定下来演出的河边奏子
highly recommended Miss Akiba whom she had never met and said she wanted to perform with the latter.
强烈推荐了素未谋面秋庭小姐 期望和她同台演出
That's how Miss Akiba was chosen for the performance.
演出就定了下来
So, the next question should be
因此接下来的问题是
the connection between those four people had with that incident.
那四人跟事件的联系
Until now, we haven't found the connection between Mr. Akiba and the four others.
至今没有找到秋庭小姐跟那四人之间的联系
The only thing we know is
知道的只有
the relationship between Miss Kabe and the two men who died in the explosion.
河边小姐和之前被炸死的两个人之间的关系
But there's still the issue of the performance...
那个同台演出的事情啊
The bomb was placed under the floor near the two men.
炸药安置在被炸死的两人附近的地板下面
If that's the case,
如果是这样的话
then Miss Kabe might just be collateral damage?
河边小姐只是被牵连的吗
It's too early to say that.
也不能那么断言
There are others with motives to hurt Miss Kabe.
至少也有人有伤害河边小姐的动机
You mean Rara Chigusa, the candidate before Miss Akiba.
就是秋庭小姐之前的候选人千草拉拉吧
We have another suspect.
还有一个人
That's Yamane Miss Shion who replaced Miss Kabe.
就是代替河边小姐的山根紫音
That person?
是那个人吗
If she borrowed Miss Kabe's Stradivari
如果向河边小姐借了斯特拉迪瓦里
and gives an excellent performance
并能在这个国际知名音乐家汇聚的音乐会上
at this concert where all the famous international musicians will gather,
出色地演奏的话
she'll become world famous overnight.
她就可以一夜之间闻名全球
But, there's one more possibility.
可是 还有一点
Though Mr. Domoto appreciates her talents,
虽然堂本先生非常欣赏她
he still asked Miss Kabe to give the performance.
但却选了河边小姐出演
It was not because of Miss Kabe herself,
实际上不是想选河边小姐本人
but the Stradivari she owned.
而是因为她拥有斯特拉迪瓦里
Mr. Domoto wanted to pick Miss Shion.
其实本来是想选紫音小姐的
That's why he chose Miss Shion to be the stand-in.
然后指名紫音小姐为代演
Then in order to get his hands on the Stradivarius,
为了借到斯特拉迪瓦里
he ensured that Miss Kabe would be seriously injured.
使河边小姐受重伤
This possibility cannot be ruled out either.
这种可能也不是没有
Their relationships are so complicated.
人际关系这么复杂
I really got confused.
让人更摸不着头脑了
Anyway,
总之
Rara Chigusa has a motive to kill Miss Kabi and Miss Akiba.
对河边小姐和怜子小姐都有动机的是千草拉拉
Mr. Domoto and Miss Shion have the motive to kill Miss Kabe.
只对河边小姐有动机的是堂本先生和紫音小姐
But we still haven't found the motive the three suspects have to kill the four victims.
但是还没有发现这三个人对那四个被害人的动机
Am I right?
是这么说吧
Yeah.
是啊
By the say, is there anything special about
对了 爆炸了的练习室里的钢琴
the piano in the practice room where the explosion occurred?
有什么特别的吗
No, I didn't hear anything special about it.
不 没听说有什么特别的
Why did you ask that?
为什么这么想呢
When I went to that place,
之前去那个地方的时候
I saw Mr. Fuwa
看到那个叫谱和的先生
taking the piano pieces away carefully as if they were very important.
把钢琴的碎片很重视般地带走了
I thought maybe there might be something special about it.
我就想也许有什么特别的东西吧
Hey, didn't I tell you to stop wandering around on your own!
喂 叫你没事别乱跑的啊
Sorry.
对不起
Mr. Domoto has played that piano at his home for 30 years.
那架钢琴堂本先生在自己家里弹了30多年
When he retired from playing the piano,
堂本先生退出钢琴界的时候
he moved the piano to the academy for the young students to play.
为了让青年乐手练习而搬到了学院里
The piano was tuned by Mr. Fuwa
无论是在堂本先生家的时候
when it was in Mr. Domoto's house
还是搬到了学院后
as well as in the academy.
调音都是谱和来做的
Perhaps to him the piano is like his child.
对他而言也许就像自己的孩子一样吧
Now do you understand, kiddo?
明白了吧 小鬼
Speaking of which,
这么说来
Mr. Fuwa seems to have a big problem with the four victims.
谱和先生好像对那四个人的意见很大
He criticized about their attitudes toward life.
说是平时的生活态度有问题
But it's impossible that he would kill them for that reason.
但是总不会就为了这些原因而杀了四个人吧
True.
也对啊
Even if their attitude toward life irritated Mr. Fuwa
就算 对他们的生活态度
so that he wanted to kill them,
已经无法忍受到想杀了他们的地步
we still can't connect him to the incident that happened to Miss Akiba.
这样 又无法和秋庭小姐的事件联系起来了
Inspector,
警部
maybe we should separate Miss Akiba's case
把秋庭小姐的案件
from the other four.
和那四个人的案件分开来考虑吧
However, those cases all connects to Mr. Domoto.
可是这么多案件发生在堂本先生的周围
Don't you find it too coincident?
你不觉得太巧合了吗
You've got a point.
也是啊
Anyway,
总而言之
we should protect Miss Akiba
至少在后天的音乐会结束之前
until the end of the concert.
考虑到需要保护秋庭小姐的安全
I remembered sending Takagi to do it.
已经派高木去了吧
Well...
那个…
She said I was too annoying and drove me out.
她说我麻烦 把我赶出来了
Seriously.
真是的
What were you thinking, Takagi?
你在干什么呢 高木
If Miss Akiba is attacked again,
如果怜子小姐再被袭击的话
not even a written apology would do you any good.
你就不是写份检讨书就能解决的了
But she said she would stay at home for the next two days.
可是她说今明两天都呆在家里
You fool!
笨蛋
Is there anyone who would just say "Oh, I see" and leave?
会有说句“啊 是这样啊”就跑回来的家伙么
I'm sorry.
十分抱歉
I'm leaving.
我走啦
Conan!
柯南
Morning, Conan!
早上好 柯南
Good morning!
早上好
What's with you guys?
你们怎么了
Coming over so early this morning?
这么一大早的
We are going to see Kamen Rider.
去见假面超人
Kamen Rider?
假面超人？
I got word that
今天早上会在堤无津川的绿地公园取景
they'll be filming in Ryokuchi Park today.
我得到的绝密情报哦
We think that Genta might recover right away after seeing that.
我们想看了那个的话元太也许就会康复了
He seems pretty okay to me.
看不出有什么不健康嘛
So we wanted you to come with us.
所以来约你一起去
Where are you going?
你要去哪里吗
I got something to do.
有点事
What is it?
什么事
Nothing serious.
没什么大不了的吧
Is it more important than your friendship with Genta?
比和元太的友谊更重要吗
I guess I have no choice.
真没办法啊
I'm going to meet Miss Reiko.
是去怜子小姐那里啦
Reiko sensei?
怜子老师啊
I don't think you should go.
还是不要去了
You'll be scolded again.
一定又会被训的
Maybe, but if I can't protect her from the bad buy...
可能吧 但如果我不从坏人手里保护她的话…
You mean the bad guy from last time?
坏人是指上次的吗
Why do you have to protect her?
为什么要柯南来保护
Why is that?
说起来这是为什么呢
I don't know.
我也不是很清楚
I just feel obliged to do it.
总觉得自己不得不这么做
He said it must be because of love.
他说那一定是爱情
Conan prefers older women.
因为柯南总喜欢比自己年纪大的
How's that possible?
这怎么可能
Anyway, please take care of Genta.
那么元太就拜托你们两个了
I'm relying on you guys!
拜托啦
Conan!
柯南
Is it because he trusts us?
是因为他信赖我们吗
Maybe.
或许吧
Hello.
你好
Morning, Miss Reiko.
早上好 怜子小姐
Excuse me.
打扰啦
Hey, you.
喂 你
Nice apartment.
不错的公寓啊
It's a quiet place.
周围好像很安静呢
Wait a minute.
你等一下
What's wrong with you? How could you barge into people's homes?
怎么回事啊 突然闯入别人的屋子
What do you want?
要做什么
I want to learn to sing.
学习唱歌啊
I was thinking of some intensive training.
想请你帮我特训一下
Wait a moment, you are that tone-deaf boy, aren't you?
说起来 你就是那个音痴吧
Not today.
但是今天不行
Are you going out today?
要出门吗
I heard that you would go soak in the forest air one day before important concerts
听说在重要的音乐会或录音的前一天
in order to relax your mind.
你为了放松情绪会去做森林浴
Since you know that, why did you come?
你既然知道为什么还来
I want to go with you.
我也想一起去
Gosh, didn't I tell you that
真是的 之前不是说过了吗
nothing good happens when I am with you guys.
和你们在一起没什么好事
So I don't want you to stay around me.
所以不想呆在你们身边
You only said those harsh words to protect us, right?
说这些话疏远我们其实是为了我们的安全着想
That's because you are sure that you are the target of the culprit.
因为你已经确定了犯人的目标是你自己
When you said you wanted to go to Genta's house,
那个时候说要去元太家里
it wasn't because you wanted to tell his parents on him,
不是去向他的家长告状
but because you wanted to get Genta safely home.
其实是为了将元太安全送回家吧
What nonsense are you talking about?
说什么傻话呢
By the way, can I have some juice before we leave?
对了 出门前给我果汁好吗
I'm so thirsty.
口好渴哦
Fine.
真没办法
I only have 100% orange juice.
只有100%的橙汁
Don't expect too much.
不要奢求什么了哦
That'll do.
就那个好了
Flute.
长笛
And the man.
还有那个男人
Hey,
喂
it's ten years too soon for you to be interested in a lady's bedroom!
对女性的卧室有兴趣 未免早了十年吧
Miss Reiko, do you play the flute too?
怜子小姐也吹长笛吗
It's none of your business.
和你无关吧
Go back home after you're done drinking that.
喝了这杯就快点回去
I won't teach you how to sing
不会教你唱歌的
or take you to the forest.
也不会带你去森林
Okay.
是
I'll just follow you there. Don't mind me.
我擅自跟着你去 你别在意
Geez. See if I care when you get lost.
真是的 迷路了我可不管哦
It's fine. It's fine.
没关系 没关系
Inspector Megure, we found the connection between the four men and Miss Akiba.
目暮警部 那四个人和秋庭小姐的联系查到了
What?
什么
Three years ago in January, in the dormitory of Domoto Music Academy in Izu,
三年前的一月在伊豆的堂本音乐学院的宿舍里
the flute player who lived with them got drunk
和他们住在一起的长笛演奏家因为喝醉酒
and fell off the cliff near their dormitory.
从宿舍附近的山崖上摔下而身亡
His name is Soma Hikaru and he died at the age of 28.
他叫相马光 当时28岁
He's a student from the class of 6 of Domoto Music Academy.
是堂本音乐学院的第6届学生
Did they...
难道是他们…
Yes, the four men got him drunk knowing that he was bad at drinking,
对 是那四个人强行灌醉了不会喝酒的他
However, what they had done didn't cause him to fall off the cliff directly,
因为和坠崖事件没有直接关系
so that incident was designated as an accident.
作为不幸的意外事故而被处理了
That accounts for it.
原来如此
So why is it related to Miss Akiba?
那么和秋庭小姐的联系是？
In fact, Mr. Soma is Miss Akiba's fiance.
实际上那位相马先生是秋庭小姐的未婚夫
What?
什么
Inspector.
警部
Actually, it's very possible that
的确 到现在为止
she still hates those four men until now.
她还恨着那四个人的可能性很高
Then why was she attacked too?
那么为什么她自己也受到攻击了呢
♪ Kamen Rider, if you call his name ♪
假面超人战士 大家呼唤他名字的话
♪ Kamen Rider, he'll show up at any time ♪
假面超人战士 无论何时他都会出现
Hello.
你好
Hi.
你们好
Are they mother and son?
那两个人是母子吗
They don't look alike at all.
长得一点都不像
Why are they keeping a distance from each other?
为什么隔着一段距离在走啊
Maybe he got his mother mad?
是不是他惹妈妈生气了
Seriously.
真是的
Hey, do you know why I would take a walk in the forest
喂 你知道我为什么要在音乐会前一天
one day before the concert?
到森林里来散步吗
Because I want to absorb nature into my body.
因为我想将大自然吸收到身体里
That's because European music was born out of nature.
欧洲的音乐是在大自然的包围中诞生的
Can you understand that?
你可以了解吗
I think I do.
我想我了解
Are you all right, Miss Reiko?
你没事吧 怜子小姐
Run!
快逃
You go first!
你先跑
The attack came like I expected...
果然来袭击了么
Oh no!
不好
She'll be shot.
要被射中了
Miss Reiko, this way!
怜子小姐 这边
Why... why didn't the person pull the trigger?
为什么 为什么没开枪
What does he want...
那人的目标究竟是…
Hey, I think we should inform the police.
喂 还是报警比较好吧
No, I just told you, if we call the police...
不行 我刚才也说了 如果报警的话
You said there would be delays and you would miss the concert tomorrow, right?
你说会耽误时间 会影响明天的音乐会对吧
I know that too.
虽然这个我也知道
Then stop talking.
知道的话就别说了
After the concert, I'll tell the police what happened.
这次音乐会结束后 我会跟警察说明的
Do you understand?
知道了吗
Okay.
是啦
Officer Takagi,
高木刑警
Miss Akiba and Conan.
秋庭小姐 柯南也在
Miss Akiba, where did you go?
秋庭小姐 你去哪里了
Didn't you say that you wouldn't go anywhere today?
你不是说今天哪里也不会去吗
I went out on a date with this boy.
我和这个孩子约会去了
D...date?
约…约会？
Miss Akiba, there's something we need to ask you.
秋庭小姐 我们有些话要问你
Not now.
以后再说吧
It's about Mr. Soma.
是相马光先生的事情
Mr. Soma was your fiance, right?
相马光先生是你的未婚夫吧
Officer, I'll tell you everything I know.
警部先生 我知道的事情都会说的
But please wait until the end of the concert tomorrow.
所以请等到明天的音乐会结束后
Inspector, did Mr. Soma have a mole here?
警部先生 相马先生是不是在这里有颗痣
Yes, how did you know that?
是的 为什么你会知道
Because I saw his photo in Miss Reiko's apartment.
因为在怜子小姐房间里放着照片呢
You've been to Miss Akiba's room?
你到秋庭小姐的房间里去过了吗
Yeah. Please send me home. I'll tell you everything I know.
对了 把我送回家吧 我把知道的都告诉你们
So, that's why we sent Conan back.
所以说 我们就把柯南送回来了
But in the end, the only thing he knows is that
结果他知道的只有
there's Mr. Soma's photo and a flute in her room.
她的房间里放着相马先生的照片和长笛
Geez.
真是的
But inspector,
不过警部大人
even if she has the motive to kill the four men,
就算她有杀害那四个人的动机
we still can't say that she's the murderer, right?
也不能就断定她是凶手吧
She was nearly hit by the truck after all.
她也被卡车攻击了
I mean, maybe it's Mr. Soma's family who wants to avenge him?
我说 相马先生有没有可能为他报复的其他亲戚
No, I don't think that's possible.
不 好像没有啊
Please have some tea.
那个 请喝茶吧
Thanks.
谢谢
Sorry to trouble you, Ran.
麻烦了啊 小兰
Help yourself.
请用
His mother was a single mom and passed away five years ago.
他的母亲是所谓的未婚妈妈 5年前去世了
He didn't have any siblings.
没有兄弟姐妹
What about his father?
父亲呢
I have no idea.
不知道
I don't even know if he's still alive.
是不是还活在人世也不得而知
What is that...
那个是…
There's one other issue with those four that died.
被杀害的四个人也惹出过其他的一些事
They once performed a concert while drunk.
他们曾经醉酒后在音乐会上演奏
After that, they were given a good scolding by Mr. Domoto.
后来被堂本先生大骂了一通
What? When did that happen?
什么 那是什么时候的事
Well, actually, it's, I got it.
是 是 那个 有了
It was on the concert a year ago.
是一年前的音乐会
The piece they played was Beethoven's Piano Quartet.
演奏曲目是贝多芬的《钢琴四重奏》
I know it now, Officer.
我知道了 警部大人
I know the one who killed the four men, injured Miss Kabe,
杀死那四个人 让河边小姐受了重伤
and attacked Miss Akiba. Also his motive.
并袭击了秋庭小姐的犯人 还有动机
Really, Mouri?
真的吗 毛利老弟
The culprit is
是的 那个犯人就是
Genya Domoto. It's you!
堂本弦也先生 就是你
The reason is that you worship Beethoven a lot,
原因就是 你是贝多芬的崇拜者
and,
而且是
you are obsessed with him.
超级迷恋的那种类型
What are you talking about all of a sudden?
你突然说些什么啊
You killed the four men
你杀了那四人
because they played Beethoven's piece when they were drunk.
是因为他们喝醉酒后演奏了贝多芬的曲子
They violated the sanctity of that great composer.
这是对那位伟大的作曲家的一种亵渎
You hurt Miss Kabe because
让河边小姐受重伤
when you performed with her,
是因为你以前和她合奏的时候
you two had strong disagreements on the interpretation of the piece.
对曲子的理解上有着强烈的分歧
There's a detailed account of that in Miss Kabe's essays.
这个在河边小姐写的散文里被详细记载了
Next, you attacked Miss Akiba because she said that,
接着袭击秋庭小姐是因为她在彩排的时候
"You are not going to sing the Ninth, are you?
你们合唱的该不会是“第九”吧
I hate that song."
我很讨厌那首
That was an insult to Beethoven's Ninth Symphony.
因为她说了贝多芬《第九交响曲》的坏话
Wait a minute!
请等一下
I do love and respect Beethoven a lot.
我的确是喜欢贝多芬也很尊敬他
But I'm not that crazy.
但是我还没到狂热的程度
No, I'm sure of it.
不 不会错的
The fact that you have the same haircut as him is the proof.
你留着和贝多芬一模一样的发型就是证据
M-Mouri.
毛 毛利老弟
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
This is my natural hairstyle!
这个发型是天生的
I inherited from my deceased mother.
只是和我去世的母亲很相像而已
If you don't believe me,
如果你不相信的话
please look at this!
请看
Oh, really.
真 真的呢
They look very alike.
很像啊
Now what? My motive to hurt those four men and Miss Akiba
怎么样 关于那四个人和秋庭小姐
can only be my adoration to Beethoven.
除了贝多芬其他扯不上什么关系
Miss Kabe and I are both musicians.
河边小姐和我都是音乐家
We always argue because of out differing interpretations of music,
经常会围绕乐曲的诠释而激烈争论
but that's limited to the performance!
但是 那都是演奏上的事情
It's ridiculous of you to think that
就因为这个原因而怀恨对方
I would hate her for that reason.
真是太可笑了 完全不可理喻
No, but...
不 可是…
Inspector,
警部先生
did you pay a visit to us in the middle of the night
就是为了让我们听这种荒唐的推理
to let us hear this absurd deduction?
而深夜来访的吗
We have a very important concert tomorrow.
而且明天还有非常重要的音乐会
We understand.
这我们非常理解
Anyway, please go back tonight.
总之今晚请回吧
When the concert is over, you can ask us anything you want
音乐会结束后调查什么的都行
and we will definitely cooperate with you.
配合你们直到满意为止
I thought I was totally correct.
我还以为肯定没错呢
Where did you get that confidence from?
那自信到底是哪里来的啊
Officer Takagi,
高木刑警
hasn't Miss Kabe regained her memory?
河边小姐的记忆还没有回复吗
Well, we could finally talk to her,
是啊 总算可以谈些话了
but she kept saying how the pitch of the sound the air conditioner makes and can't sleep.
但是她却说很在意空调的声音有音差
She's saying all sorts of incomprehensible things.
而无法入睡之类的很难理解的话
The pitch of the sound the air conditioner make? Could it be...
空调的声音有音差？难道说…
You don't need to take it now, right?
不用一开始就拿出来吧
Sorry.
抱歉
Please use this.
请用这个吧
Yes.
是
The piece they'll play are the same as the ones they will perform on the concert.
演奏内容和正式演出一模一样
Plus, we can sit anywhere we want.
而且能随意坐在自己喜欢的空座位上
Dress rehearsals are the best.
最终彩排真是太棒了
We'll be seated upstairs during the public performance.
正式演出的位子在楼上
I asked my dad to book the seats for us.
我拜托爸爸帮忙的
Those are the VIP seats.
那不是舞台剧的特等席吗
There are ten seats, which could hold all of us.
座位有10个 我们正好包下
Ten of us?
有10个人吗
I also invited Professor Agasa and the kids.
我还邀请了阿笠博士和孩子们
I invited Shinichi too.
还有就是新一啊
You should inform him.
告诉他吧
Tell him I left the ticket at the reception desk.
跟他说把门票留在了接待处了
I don't think it's necessary.
那个家伙不用了啦
It's fine. Hurry up. Or the ticket will be wasted.
没关系啦 快点 否则座位不是浪费了吗
All right.
真没办法
But I don't think he'll come.
我想他是不会来的
Sorry, Ran.
对不起了 小兰
It seems you didn't tell the police what happened yesterday.
昨天的事你没有告诉警察啊
Thank you.
还是要谢谢你了
Never mind that.
那是不用了
How's your leg?
不过你脚伤没事了吗
It won't affect my singing.
影响不了唱歌
Miss Soko Kabe has perfect pitch too, doesn't she?
河边奏子小姐也有绝对音感吧
Yes, I figured that out when we first met.
是啊 见面的时候得知的
We got along pretty well.
就更加志同道合了
Does that mean something?
那又怎么了
Nothing.
没什么
Is that so? Well, I'll go now.
是吗 那我先走了
I hope the concert goes well.
音乐会加油啊
Miss Reiko and Miss Kabe both have perfect pitch.
怜子小姐和河边小姐都拥有绝对音感
If so...
这样的话…
I'll get angry again if I talk to him on the phone, so I emailed him.
跟他用电话讲会生气 所以发邮件过去了
Oh, I hope Shinichi could come.
是吗 新一能来就好了呢
Whatever.
我可是无所谓的
I just don't want the ticket to be wasted.
只是觉得座位太浪费了
That's what I said before.
这个是我刚才说的
Really?
是吗
It can't be helped, let's begin without him.
没办法 不管他我们先开始吧
What happened?
发生什么事了吗
Mr. Mouri, Mr. Muller hasn't shown up yet.
毛利先生 谬勒先生还没有来
The organ tuner?
那个管风琴调律师吗
He said he would come to the dress rehearsal to do the fine tuning.
约好会来参加最终彩排 为我们稍做调整的
This is really troublesome.
真是麻烦
He didn't answer his calls either.
打他电话也不接
The people from the hotel said that he didn't come back since last night.
宾馆的人说他从昨晚开始就没回来
Since last night?
从昨晚吗
Anyway, we only need him to do the fine tuning. It won't be a big problem if he can't come.
不过只剩下微调整 他不来的话也没有什么大碍
But doesn't it mean that he went missing?
但是那不是失踪了吗
Did you tell the police?
报警了吗
Not yet. The questioning will take too much time.
没有 又要被问东问西会耽误时间的
We have to focus on the concert now.
总之现在要把精力集中在音乐会上
Miss Shion looks like a different person.
紫音小姐像换了个人似的
♪ Ave maria ♪
Ave maria
♪ Gratia plena ♪
Gratia plena
♪ Dominus tecum ♪
Dominus tecum
The sound...
这个声音…
♪ Benedicta tu in mulieribus ♪
Benedicta tu in mulieribus
Miss Shion played the violin so well!
紫音小姐的小提琴好棒啊
That's right! It was completely different from the last rehearsal!
真的呢 和彩排的时候截然不同呢
It's like the Stradivari actually belongs to her.
完全把斯特拉迪瓦里当作自己的小提琴了
What do you know?
你懂什么呀
Miss Reiko's singing was wonderful as well.
还有怜子小姐的歌声也很棒啊
Conan!
柯南
You guys are too early.
你们太早了吧
That's because you aren't allowed in even if you're only one minute late.
迟到一分钟的话就不能进去了呀
So we asked the professor to bring us here early.
我们拜托博士早点来了
What's in your hand?
你拿着什么呢
Isn't that a recorder?
那不是竖笛吗
You idiot, no one would bring that to a classical music concert.
你傻呀 有谁会在古典音乐会上带这个来的
Don't tell at him. He can't speak now,
别生气呀 元太不能说话
so he wants to make sound with that.
所以至少想发点声音呀
Even so.
所以呀
Of course, he won't make a sound during the concert.
当然在演奏的时候是不会出声的
Right,  Genta?
对吧 元太
It means, yes.
这个意思就是yes
Remember to hide it when you get into the hall.
在会场里给我藏好啊
You can't use your cellphones either.
手机也是禁止开的哦
They know. They didn't even bring their detective boys badge.
知道的啦 侦探徽章也没带来呢
I'm hungry.
我肚子饿了
Then let's go get something to eat.
那么我们随便去吃点什么吧
That's right. The concert will be at 5 o'clock.
也对 演出是5点
We can't let our stomach grumble in the middle of the concert.
期间肚子叫了的话可不行啊
He's saying grilled eel over rice.
他在说鳗鱼饭 鳗鱼饭
If only we could all communicate with recorders.
用竖笛能说话就好了呢
Well, that's not impossible.
那个嘛 也不是不行哟
We just need to turn the notes into letters.
把音符换成文字就行了
The notes?
音符？
To letters?
换成文字吗
However, using English letters might still be difficult for Kojima.
不过因为是字母 对于小岛同学还是太难了点
There really is something wrong with that sound.
我还是很在意那个音啊
Miss Ran, I just remembered something I have to do.
小兰姐姐 我突然想起一件事来
I'll go to my seat before the performance.
开演前我一定会到座位上去的
Wait, Conan!
等一下 柯南
What a selfish brat.
真是个任性的家伙
That note! Isn't that note a little weird?
那个音 那个音是不是有点奇怪
I think so too.
我也这么觉得
I noticed that when I was singing.
唱歌的时候注意到的
However, though I know which key it is,
但是 虽然知道了是哪个键
I don't know which stop it was.
却不知道是哪个音栓的音色
That's because there are several of them making sound.
因为有好几根在发声
It does sound slightly flat.
果然略微低了一点
I'm sure of it.
不会有错的
The sound came from there.
声音是从那边传来的
I think it should be one of the short pipes on the inside.
我觉得应该是内侧的短音管
One of them definitely needs tuning.
看来有一根没有调准音
We have to fix it before the performance.
得在正式演出之前修好
But we still don't know where Mr. Muller is.
但是谬勒先生不是下落不明吗
Indeed.
的确
Anyway, let's inform Mr. Domoto first.
总之先去通知堂本先生
It seems that he's not here.
好像不在啊
Yes.
是啊
Maybe he went to have some tea.
会不会是去喝茶了
Or maybe he's there...
或者是在那儿
By the way, I'm surprised that you noticed.
说起来 你居然能注意到那个音
My ears are sharp.
我的耳朵很灵哦
This is great.
这不是很好吗
Maybe you have perfect pitch too.
说不定你也有绝对音感哦
That'll be the best.
那样就好了
Mr. Domoto is not here.
堂本先生不在呢
Could he be somewhere else?
有没有别的他可能在的地方呢
Well.
是啊
Maybe it's like what you said, he went to have tea.
说不定就像你说的 去喝茶了
Attention, ladies and gentlemen,
各位来宾请注意
smoking is permitted only in the designated areas.
会场内除了吸烟室之外一律禁烟
Akiba is still not here?
秋庭还没到吗
Yes, she didn't answer the phone either.
是啊 我打她手机也没人接
The staffs are also looking for her now.
正在让工作人员到周围找
Did she go missing too?
不会也失踪了吧
I don't know.
我也不知道
First it was Mr. Muller, now even she is...
先是谬勒先生 连她也…
What is happening here?
到底是怎么回事
The concert will start in 15 minutes.
离开演只有15分钟了
If she still hasn't shown up...
如果她还是没有出现的话…
Please give me the chance.
请让我代替吧
After what happened to Miss Kabe,
因为发生了河边小姐的事件
I thought that this might happen.
我猜想可能会这样
So I have been practicing.
所以一直都在练习
But...
但是
Please, sir!
拜托了 老师
I'll do a better job than Akiba.
我一定会比秋庭唱得好的
You don't need to be better.
不需要比她好
Music is the plea from humans to God.
音乐是人类向神明的发问
You have to sing as if you are praying.
要如同祈祷一般的歌唱
Shinichi didn't turn up after all...
新一果然没有来
Speaking of, what happened to Conan?
说起来柯南到底怎么了
The concert is about to start.
都快开始了
Really, where did Conan go?
真的呢 柯南到底上哪儿去了
But if it's Conan, I'm sure he'll be fine.
但是柯南的话一定不用担心的
I trust him.
我相信他
Me too.
是啊
Just like Conan trusts us,
就像柯南相信我们一样
we should trust him too.
我们也要相信他
Conan is going to be all right.
柯南的话一定会没事的
Attention, ladies and gentlemen,
各位来宾请注意
Miss Akiba won't be performing today
原本今天由秋庭怜子小姐进行的演出
due to some unforeseen reasons.
因故变更
Taking her place for this performance is
代替其演出的是
Rara Chigusa, the student from the class of 9 of Domoto Music Academy.
堂本音乐学院第9届学生 千草拉拉小姐
We apologize for the inconvenience caused.
为此带来的不便敬请谅解
What's happened?
怎么回事
She did a wonderful job during the dress rehearsal.
彩排的时候她明明唱得那么好
Could it be that she and Shinichi are in trouble?
不会是和新一一起出事了吧
Plastic sheet?
塑料布？
What has happened?
怎么回事
Miss Reiko, Miss Reiko!
怜子小姐 怜子小姐
What?
怎么了
Where is this place?
这是 哪里
Probably the downstream of the canal.
应该是运河的下游
The guy who attacked us
袭击我们的犯人
must have set us adrift from the lake behind Domoto Hall and let the canal carry us here.
将我们从堂本音乐厅后面的池子冲到运河来了
But, who would...
但是 到底是谁…
I have no idea.
不知道
Also, why did that person put us on a boat
而且 为什么特意打晕我们之后
after knocking us out.
把我们放到小船上
Anyway, if we can't get back in time,
总之如果不赶快回去的话
the concert will be...
音乐会就…
But, even if we can swim that distance,
但是 就算能游过去
the wall is still too high for us to climb.
那墙也太高根本就爬不上去
There doesn't seem to be anyone around.
好像没有人
But, look,
但是 你看
there's a phone on the wall.
那儿的墙上有电话
If we can't reach it, we can call for help.
如果能够着的话 就能求救了
Wait, even if we can't reach it,
等等 就算够不着
we can still phone for help if we take down the receiver
如果能取下听筒的话说不定也能求救
But how could we do it?
那要怎么做呢
When we dial the numbers to make a call,
用按键式电话机打电话的时候
there'll be "pi, po, pa" sounds, right?
不是会有“噼啵啪”的声音吗
That's DTMF signal.
注：DTMF信号即双音多频(Dual Tone Multi Frequency)信号，通常用于发送被叫号码。 它由高频群和低频群组成，各4个频率，一个高频信号和一个低频信号叠加组成一个组合信号。 那个被称为DTMF信号
Through a combination of low and high signals
通过高低两个信号音的组合
to transmit the telephone number.
来识别所拨的号码
So, if we can successfully produce those sounds...
因此 如果能顺利发出这个声音的话
We'll be able to dial the number, right?
也就能拨打电话了对吧
The number 1 should be 697Hz and 1209Hz,
110的“1”应该是697Hz和1209Hz
the number 0 should be the combination of 941Hz and 1336Hz.
“0”是941Hz和1336Hz的组合
No problem.
没问题
I can remember the dial sounds.
按键电话机的声音 我记得
But we have to take the receiver down first.
但是 得先取下听筒
I've got that covered.
这就交给我吧
The problem is that, after we take it down,
问题是 取下听筒后一段时间后
we won't be able to make a call again.
就不能再打电话了
Which means, we only have one chance.
也就是说 机会只有一次
If we fail, we could only wait for someone to find us.
如果失败的话 就只能等别人找到我们了
We don't have any time to waste.
没这么多时间等了
Let's do it.
只有干了
Since we've decided to do it,
既然决定了
let's do the rehearsal now.
就马上彩排吧
What was that?
刚才是什么
The sound of an explosion. Something exploded!
爆炸声 有东西爆炸了
It was in the direction of the Domoto Concert Hall.
是堂本音乐厅的方向
Could it be...
难道…
We are at the music forest in Nishitamashi.
这里是西多摩市的音乐森林
Just moments ago, two explosions occurred here at the Domoto Concert Hall.
就在刚才 堂本音乐厅发生了两次爆炸
The blast took place in the innermost left of the concert hall
分别是音乐厅左边最内侧
and the entrance of the greenroom which is on the middle right.
和右边中间的演员休息室入口
The concert started five minutes ago.
音乐会在5分钟之前就开演了
We still don't know the situation inside...
内部的情况还…
Another explosion.
又爆炸了
Hurry! The sound of the number "0".
赶快 接下来是“0”的声音
It should work.
应该能行
Let's row the boat over.
把船划过去
We can do it here. Stop.
这儿就行 停船
Now what? How are you going to take the receiver down?
然后呢 你要怎么取下听筒呢
Just wait and see.
你就看着吧
Amazing.
好厉害
Now, let's start!
开始吧
Hello, this is 110 communication room.
你好 这里是110通信指挥室
Miss Akiba and Conan?
秋庭小姐和柯南吗
They seemed to have been washed downstream on a boat
他们好像被人打晕后
after they were knocked out.
放在船上冲到运河下游去了
The location is Nishitama Reservoir Water Temperature Management Office.
地点是西多摩市 西多摩水库水温管理处
They are here!
来了
I see them! Over there!
看见了 在那儿
So it was from Domoto Concert Hall.
果然是堂本音乐厅吗
There have been more than 10 explosions
已经发生了10次以上的爆炸
which took place at the pillars outside the building.
都发生在建筑物外围的柱子
We haven't found the cause of the explosion.
原因还未查明
Someone planted the bombs there.
是有人放置了炸弹
Though we still don't know if the bombs were set off by a timer or a remote control,
虽然还不知道是使用的定时器还是遥控器
I think the culprit might be the same person who killed the four men.
应该和杀害那四人的是同一个犯人
That's right. The first incident was also an explosion.
的确 最初的事件也是爆炸案
But, why did that person leave us in a place far away from the concert hall instead of killing us?
但是 为什么只是将我们置于离音乐厅这么远的地方而不杀了我们呢
Could it be that she's...
难道她…
Another one.
又爆炸了
Hey, can we get in touch with the people in there?
喂 和里面能取得联系吗
Miss Ran and Mr. Mouri are still inside the building.
小兰姐姐和叔叔他们在里面
We can't get through.
内线电话打不通
The culprit may have cut the telephone lines.
也许是电话线被犯人切断了
What about their cellphones?
但是手机之类的呢
It's pointless.
没用的
It's a basic etiquette to turn off cellphones during a performance.
在演出中关闭手机是基本礼节
Except for certain areas, there's no cell service in the concert hall.
音乐厅内除了个别地方 都没有信号
Besides, people inside the hall should be safe.
而且 内部应该不会有事的
That's because the hall is completely soundproof and fireproof.
因为音乐厅内是完全防音完全防火的
Maybe the people there didn't even notice the explosion.
也许连发生了爆炸都没注意到
Which means the concert might still be going on now.
那么说音乐会可能仍在进行
I think so.
我想是这样的
But, maybe the explosion will not only happen at the places outside the hall.
但是 不一定只有外围会发生爆炸
It will extend to the inside.
总会炸到内部的
No, maybe it already did.
不 也许已经发生了
Ran.
小兰
♪ Und sich mir zu eigen gibet ♪
Und sich mir zu eigen gibet
♪ Ach drum laß ich Jesum nicht ♪
Ach drum laß ich Jesum nicht
♪ Wenn mir gleich mein Herze bricht ♪
Wenn mir gleich mein Herze bricht
Good evening, everyone.
各位晚上好
Welcome to the concert.
欢迎各位今日的光临
I am Genya Domoto.
我是堂本一挥
As you know, tonight, we finally...
正如大家所知 今晚终于在这…
Come over here! This way!
快到这里来 这边这边
What are you doing? Hurry and get that hose over here!
在干吗呢 快把水管拿过来
This is serious.
真过分
But the hall in the middle seems fine.
但是中间的大厅没有爆炸
The people inside should be fine.
里面的人一定不会有事的
It's too soon to be relieved.
要高兴还早了点
The entrance to the hall have been all blocked.
能从外面进去的地方都被堵死了
A rescue operation would be impossible!
这样根本就没办法营救
How could it be like this?
怎么会这样
What's more, we don't know which pillar will explode next.
而且接下去哪根柱子会爆炸还不知道
There are 23 pillars surrounding the building.
外围的柱子一共是23根
Does the bomber want to blow all the pillars off?
难不成犯人打算全都炸毁吗
Damn it, what should we do?
可恶 该怎么办啊
We can only get in from the roof.
只有从房顶进入了
Is it possible?
能行吗
We can manage to do that now.
现在的话应该勉强能行
But, there isn't a proper parking apron.
但是 这里没有正规的停机坪
I don't know if the roof can bear the weight of the helicopter.
不知道屋顶能不能承受直升机的重量
I see.
明白了
Please get as low as you could.
请下降到尽可能低的高度
Then we'll jump out.
然后我们跳下去
I'll lead the way.
我来带路
The access from the roof to the fourth floor is very complicated.
从屋顶下到4楼的通道非常复杂
Therefore...
所以
But...
但是这个…
We don't have time to think, do we?
已经没时间考虑了 不是吗
Now that the explosions have stopped, we should hurry!
趁现在爆炸暂时停止的时候 赶快
Lower,
再低一点
a bit lower.
还差一点
I can't go any lower.
不能再低了
The air flow is less steady than I thought.
气流比想象中更糟糕
I can't keep the helicopter balanced.
飞机无法停稳
You need to get off now.
趁现在快下去
Come on, Miss Akiba.
来 秋庭小姐
Conan, you should stay in the helicopter.
柯南 你就这样呆在直升机里…
Conan.
柯南
I'll stay here
我也要留在这里
until Miss Ran and everybody else are saved.
直到小兰姐姐和大家被救出来为止
Conan.
柯南
Also, I've seen the culprit's face.
而且我看到过犯人的脸
Though I don't know who the bomber is,
虽然不知道爆炸犯是谁
I've seen the person who attacked us.
但我看到过袭击我们的犯人
Maybe he's somewhere in the concert hall, so...
说不定他就在这个音乐厅里面 所以…
Hurry up, I can't hold it anymore.
快一点 坚持不住了
Fine, we have to take him.
没办法 只能带着他了
Takagi, hurry!
高木 赶快
Yes!
是
This is the interior corridor on the fourth floor.
这里是4楼的内部走廊
Didn't we simple descend directly from the top?
不是直接就走下来了吗
If I didn't say that, you wouldn't have let me come, would you?
如果我不那么说的话 你们是不会让我下来的吧
I did the same thing as this boy.
和这个孩子一样
Did you really see the face of the culprit?
你真的看到犯人的脸了吗
What a surprise.
还真令人吃惊
Though we expected that, I'm still shocked that the people here really haven't noticed the explosions.
虽然料到了 但没想到里面对爆炸真的毫无感觉
Anyway, let's find the bombs first.
总之先找炸弹吧
It's impossible to evacuate so many people at once.
要一下子疏散这么多人根本不可能
Besides, if the target is the concert hall,
而且 如果目的是要破坏音乐厅的话
there have to be bombs set up inside the hall.
音乐厅的内部应该也设置了炸弹
I understand.
明白了
Conan, you should stay here with Miss Akiba.
柯南 你和秋庭小姐乖乖呆在这儿
I know.
知道了
Let's go.
走吧
Yes.
是
Ran,
小兰
wait for me.
等着我
The inside, what's the situation inside?
内部 内部是什么情况
♪ Come unto Him all ye that labour ♪
Come unto Him all ye that labour
♪ Come unto Him that are heavy laden ♪
Come unto Him that are heavy laden
♪ And He will give you rest ♪
And He will give you rest
The culprit knows the structure of the hall very well
犯人是个熟知这个音乐厅的构造
and planted bombs here.
并设置了炸弹的人
It has to be one of the staff members.
恐怕是工作人员中的某个人
The sound is very weird.
这个声音果然很奇怪
Even Mr. Domoto didn't notice.
连堂本先生也没注意到
If it's a piano, he would have noticed it.
如果是钢琴的话他就能注意到了
He's only been playing the organ for two years, so he probably couldn't tell the difference between the sound.
刚弹了两年 也许注意不到声音的差异吧
The difference between the sound?
声音的差异？
With a bunch of amateurs who can't tell the difference in sound...
跟一群不懂声音的差异的外行人…
So that's what it was about...
原来是这样
Miss Kabe noticed the difference,
河边小姐注意到了差异
because she has perfect pitch.
因为她有绝对音感
Wait, if that's the case, then why did that person...
等等 这样的话为什么那个人…
Could it be, that person...
难道说 那个人…
If so,
如果是这样的话
why did he attack her...
为什么要对她…
His mother is a single mom.
他的母亲是未婚妈妈
I see. I know everything.
原来如此 是这样啊
But what does the difference in sounds have to do with the explosion?
但是 声音的差异和爆炸有什么关系呢
By the way, I just noticed this.
说起来 我刚注意到
But the explosions stopped during
之前爆炸停止的时候
Mr. Domoto's speech, right?
正好是堂本先生致词的时候对吧
Is it really because the culprit didn't want others to hear the sound of the explosion?
难道真的是不想让别人注意到爆炸声吗
No, it can't be.
不对 不是这样的
The bomb will only be set off when the performance starts.
如果不演奏的话就不会爆炸
I get it. That why the sound is different.
原来如此 所以声音才会不同
It's that sound again.
又是那个音
How many times did you hear that sound?
那个音出现过几次
From the beginning of the concert,
从音乐会开始到现在
do you remember how many times that key appears?
那个不准的音出现了几次 你知道吗
It should be
应该是
twice in Ave Maria.
在最初的《圣母颂》的两次
Ten times in the chorus,
之后的大合唱 有10次
eight times in the piece which is being performed now.
现在演奏中的曲目有8次
So it's 20 times in total.
一共是20次
So, there are still four times left.
那么 恐怕还剩下4次
That sound is linked to the explosion.
那个音跟爆炸是联动的
That's why there was no explosion when Mr. Domoto gave the speech.
所以在堂本先生致词的时候没有发生爆炸
There are 23 pillars surrounding the hall,
音乐厅外围的柱子一共是23根
which means
也就是说
the bomber needs to create 24 explosions
炸毁外围所有的柱子
in order to destroy all the pillars
并让音乐厅内部发生爆炸的话
and the concert hall.
需要24次爆炸
You mean...
也就是说
Yes.
是的
If we can't stop the performance
在接下来那个音响起4次之前
before that sound shows up for 4 times,
不让演奏停下来的话
this concert hall will be blown up.
这个音乐厅内的炸弹就会爆炸
It's that sound again.
又是那个音
Shoot, I was right about it.
该死 果然是和那个音有关系的
The culprit should be watching somewhere.
犯人应该正在哪儿看着
There it is again.
又响了
I found him.
找到了
So it was that person after all.
果然是那个人
I have an idea. I'll stop the performance on the stage.
有了 我到台上去阻止演奏
Wait.
等等
If we stop it abruptly,
如果随便阻止的话
the culprit will use a remote to set off the bomb.
犯人打算用遥控器来引爆
I saw the criminal holding a remote.
我看到了 拿着遥控器的犯人
But...
可是…
Damn it, what should I do?
该死 该怎么办
Isn't there a clever way to stop the performance?
难道就没有巧妙地让演奏停下的方法吗
Or a way to change the culprit's mind?
就没有让犯人动摇的办法吗
Three minutes.
3分钟
Will three minutes be enough?
如果有3分钟够吗
But...
但是…
Then you are in charge now, young detective.
那就交给你了哦 小侦探
♪ So lange ich Dich höre ♪
So lange ich Dich höre
♪ Glaub'ich an uns're Liebe ♪
Glaub'ich an uns're Liebe
♪ Amazing Grace ♪
Amazing Grace
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
How sweet the sound
♪ That sav'd a wretch like me! ♪
That sav'd a wretch like me!
It's Miss Reiko.
是怜子老师
The song
这首歌
is "Amazing Grace".
是《奇异恩典》啊
♪ I once was lost, but now am found ♪
I once was lost, but now am found
♪ Was blind, but now I see ♪
Was blind, but now I see
What's she up to now?
现在来算什么啊
♪ Amazing Grace ♪
Amazing Grace
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
How sweet the sound
♪ That sav'd a wretch like me! ♪
That sav'd a wretch like me!
♪ I once was lost, but now am found ♪
I once was lost, but now am found
♪ Was blind, but now I see ♪
Was blind, but now I see
♪ 'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear ♪
'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear
The person at that time
那时候的人
was Miss Reiko.
果然是怜子小姐
♪ 'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear ♪
'Twas grace that taught my heart to fear
♪ And grace my fears reliev'd ♪
And grace my fears reliev'd
I should have got rid of her too.
果然当时应该让她也消失吧
I won't let you do that.
消失不了的
It's this singing which could warm our hearts
这个温暖人心的歌声
that made you hesitant, right?
所以你才踌躇不定吧
Moreover, this song was
何况这首歌
your son, Mr. Soma's favorite song before he died.
是你儿子 相马光先生生前最喜欢的歌曲
And the one who's giving the performance was the person he loved.
而且正在演唱的是儿子心爱的女人
The difference in sounds
推理的关键
is the key of my deduction.
在于音色的区别
At first, we thought there was something wrong with the tuning.
刚开始 我们以为是调律有误导致音色有出入
But that wasn't the case.
可结果并非如此
Hidden in one of the pipes,
管风琴的一根风管里
must be a micro-sensor which could sense minute changes in air flow.
藏有能够感应气流的微小的传感器
Because of that,
受此影响
the sound made by that pipe is slightly off.
风管传出来的声音有了微妙的差别
Once the sensor in the pipe senses the air flow,
风管里的传感器一旦感应到气流
the bombs which you have set up will be set off one after another.
事前设置好的炸弹便会逐一接到信号而被引爆
When the last bomb explodes,
而当最后一个炸弹爆炸的时候
this concert hall will be destroyed.
也就意味着这个音乐厅的毁灭
The bombs did not explode during the dress rehearsal
最终彩排时没有爆炸
because the sensor wasn't activated.
是因为传感器并未启动
Am I right?
没有错吧
Director of Domoto Hall,
堂本音乐厅馆长
the former piano tuner, Mr. Takumi Fuwa.
原钢琴调律师 谱和匠先生
Not here.
这里也没有
This is bad.
很不妙啊
If this continues,
这样下去
the bomb will explode before we find it.
炸弹被发现前就会爆炸了
Quiet.
安静
What is that sound?
这个 是什么声音
Don't move!
别动
Police!
是警察
Mr. Muller.
谬勒先生
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
How sweet the sound
How did you know it was me?
为什么知道是我
Perfect pitch.
绝对音感
Mr. Fuwa, you have perfect pitch,
谱和先生明明拥有绝对音感
but you didn't point out the irregular sound during the dress rehearsal.
在最终彩排时却没有指出声音的差异
That made me suspicious.
因此感到很奇怪
I see.
原来如此
Then, how did you find out that I was Hikaru's father?
那么 我是光的父亲这件事呢
The plate number of your car is 52-83.
谱和先生的车牌号是52-83
You got that from your son's birthday, right?
那是取自儿子的出生日期吧
You could not proclaim your love for your son to the world,
作为与不能公之于众的心爱的儿子
so you used the number plate as a testimony of your connection to your son.
血脉相连的印证
Also, I saw a photo of you when you were young
还有 在堂本先生家里看到的
in Mr. Domoto's house.
谱和先生年轻时的照片
You look exactly the same as your son.
与儿子长得一模一样哦
You killed the four musicians
杀害那4个音乐家
to avenge for your son who died in the accident.
是为了给事故中死去的儿子报仇
You left the flute parts at the crime scene
将长笛的部件留在现场
to make the police think that there would only be three murders.
是为了误导警方连续杀人案只有3件
You got Miss Kabe involved and injured her,
牵连河边小姐 使她身负重伤
because she has perfect pitch and could tell the differences in sound.
是因为她拥有可能听出声音差异的绝对音感
Only someone who has perfect pitch
只有拥有绝对音感的人
will be afraid of another who also has that ability.
才会害怕同样拥有绝对音感的人
Judging from that, I think the culprit can only be you, Mr. Fuwa.
从这点判断 犯人也只有谱和先生了
There's another person
另外还有一个人
who has perfect pitch. That's Reiko Akiba.
秋庭怜子小姐也拥有绝对音感
However, she's the fiancee of your deceased son,
但是 对于死去的儿子的未婚妻
so you can't hurt her with a bomb
无法像对奏子小姐一样
like you did to Miss Kabe.
使用可能危及生命的炸弹
Therefore, you put an irritant drug in her drink
因此选择了往饮品中投放刺激物
and attacked her with a truck and an air gun.
以及用卡车和气枪袭击
To make her unable to perform on the stage,
为了不让她登上舞台
you only need to hurt her throat
让她无法发声
or break her ankle.
或者脚骨折就足够了
♪ Was blind, but now I see ♪
Was blind, but now I see
He improvised.
即兴演奏
He pressed on the key.
按了
How? Why didn't...
怎么会 为什么
There won't be any more explosions.
不会爆炸了哦
Before I got here,
刚才来这里前
I already removed the sensor in the pipe.
我已经把安装在风管里的传感器拆除了
In three,
三分钟
no, two minutes.
不 两分钟就解决了
Well done, kid.
干得很不错嘛 孩子
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Conan Edogawa.
江户川柯南
I'm a detective.
是个侦探
Bravo, bravo.
太精彩了 太精彩了
Found him.
找到了
He has a remote in his hand.
拿着遥控器
It's him after all.
那么果然是那个人
What do we do?
怎么办
Should we rush in before he sets off the bombs?
在他引爆前突击进去吗
No.
不行
The moment we get in, he'll press on the button.
冲进去的一瞬间 他就会用遥控器引爆的
So what should we do?
那到底该怎么做
Let's go to that room.
那个房间
Maybe we can figure out something in that room.
去那个房间的话应该能有什么办法
What will you do?
什么办法
We'll shoot him
实施狙击
before he presses on the button.
在他按下遥控器前
Unfortunately, young detective,
很遗憾 小侦探
I can set off the bombs with this remote too.
这个遥控器也能够引爆
You lost.
是你输了
Really?
是吗
It's hard to say.
还很难说啊
Why is it hard to say?
还有什么难说的
Though I don't know how you got into the concert hall,
虽然不知道你们从哪儿进入音乐厅的
seeing as how the police haven't raided the place yet,
但从警方尚无动静看来
the hall is probably engulfed in flame
我的计划很顺利 音乐厅周围正一片火海
so they are not able to come in, right?
无法进来吧
Though I didn't expect that the sensor would be removed.
传感器被拆除的确是失算
Anyway,
算了
now I can set off the bomb at any time I want.
这样一来我就能在想引爆的时候引爆了
As a farewell gift,
作为饯行
I'll send you to heaven when you are performing.
我就在演奏时送你上西天吧
Shoot, at that time...
可恶 是那个时候…
Right at the moment when you play your favorite organ,
就在你演奏你最喜欢的管风琴时
Kazuki Domoto.
堂本一挥
Conan!
柯南
No, I can't shoot him right now.
不行 这样没法射击
Great, now please start playing,
就这样 快点开始演奏吧
Domoto.
堂本
What can I do?
怎么办
I can't use my stun-gun wrist-watch.
麻醉枪不能用的话
What else can I do?
还有什么办法
Move aside, Conan.
让开啊 柯南
Please.
拜托了
Give it to me.
借一下
My recorder.
我的竖笛
My voice is back.
能出声了
Yes, that's it.
对 就这样
Damn it.
糟了
Farewell, young detective.
永别了 小侦探
Like I'd let you!
别想得逞
mi la la la fa
mi la la la fa
Shoot
SHOOT
Someone's going to shoot!
狙击
What is that sound?
这声音是什么
It's the sound that signals the end of the game.
是终场哨声
What?
什么
Freeze, police!
别动 是警察
I lost.
是我输了呢
Mr. Fuwa,
谱和先生
where are the rest of the bombs?
剩下的炸弹呢
Inside the ceiling above the stage.
舞台正上方的天花板里
Takagi, contact Inspector Megure.
高木君 联系警部
Yes.
是
Excuse me,
不好意思
can I listen to the rest of the performance?
能不能让我听到最后
I'll confess everything after that.
之后我会悉数坦白的
I see.
知道了
They finally had the fire contained.
这边的火势也终于控制住了
- We'll go over there... - Inspector!
我们马上往那边… -警部
There's an opening on the east side.
东边有一处缝隙
Okay, let's go.
好 走吧
I'll talk to you later.
再联络
Why did you set up the bombs in the concert hall.
为什么要在音乐厅里安置炸弹
I have worked as Kazuki Domoto's piano tuner for 35 years.
我作为他 堂本一挥35年来的专属调律师
I have spent half of my life with him.
走过了前半生
But two years ago,
可是两年前
he suddenly retired from playing the piano
他突然从钢琴界引退
and told me that
然后对我说
he wanted me to be the director of Domoto Concert Hall which would be fully constructed in 2 years.
希望我成为2年后建成的堂本音乐厅的馆长
Of course, I could turn him down
当然 我可以拒绝
and become a freelance tuner.
我可以自由选择继续担任调律师
But,
但是
I have been the sole tuner of Kazuki Domoto, the international pianist, for 35 years.
这35年间作为国际钢琴家堂本一挥的专属调律师
I can't accept tuning for another pianist.
我无法让自己接受别的钢琴家
My pride wouldn't allow me to.
我的自尊心不允许
Nevertheless, I am just a craftsman
虽然这么说 我也不过是一介手艺人
who can't fulfill the job as a director.
并不认为自己可以胜任馆长的工作
I was devastated by despair.
我被绝望所击垮
Two years ago, my wife died of illness.
两年前 妻子因病去世
One year after that, my son died from an accident.
一年后 儿子又死于意外
Then I lost my job as a tuner, which I considered the only thing which gives my life a meaning.
再加上失去唯一体现生存价值的调律师的工作后
I had nothing to lose.
我已经一无所有
The music I love the most
曾经那样挚爱的音乐
now sounds like noise to me.
也彻底演变成刺耳的噪音
Yes, finally, at the night when I was woken up by
是的 终于当我被睡梦中反复听到的
that sound which appears in my dream repeatedly,
那种声音魇住而惊醒的那个晚上
I decided to wipe out everything
于是我下定决心 要将一切全都抹去
in exchange for the quiet night which I used to have.
为了换回原本宁静的夜晚
I'll wipe out the four men who took away the life of my son,
夺走儿子性命的四人自然不必说
the selfish Domoto,
自私的堂本
the organ and Domoto concert hall which took away his interests in piano,
夺走他对钢琴的兴趣的管风琴与堂本音乐厅
and even the musicians all over the world and the audience
甚至还有来听管风琴演奏的
who came to hear the organ performance.
全世界的音乐家与所有听众的生命
I agreed to be the director of Domoto concert hall
我接受邀请成为了堂本音乐厅的馆长
to gain access to the organ
因为要达成对管风琴动手脚
to place the bombs in the concert hall,
在音乐厅放置炸弹的计划
I needed to become the director of the hall first.
先成为馆长才是上上策
On the other hand, the piano which was abandoned by Domoto like I was
另一方面 与我一起被堂本舍弃的钢琴
was also very pitiful.
也甚是可悲
That means...
那就是说
Blowing off the piano with the practice room
连同钢琴一起把练习室引爆
was your way of showing your love for the piano, huh?
是因为对钢琴的爱吗
That's all I have to say.
我要说的就这么多了
Next,
接下来
please call Domoto over.
请把堂本叫来
Mr. Fuwa, calm down!
谱和先生 冷静
Don't worry,
请放心
I'll only use this to kill myself.
这是用来自杀的
I have no intention of hurting anyone else.
我无意伤害各位
Conan, leave this room.
柯南 离开这个房间
No, you committed a serious crime
不行 你犯下滔天大罪
and now you want to end your life without atoning for your sin.
在未赎罪前就想结束生命
I won't allow such cunning action.
这种狡猾的行为我不允许
Conan!
柯南
Mr. Fuwa, please don't do anything stupid.
谱和先生 不要做傻事
Shut up, I want Domoto here!
住嘴 快叫堂本过来
Fuwa,
谱和老弟
I am right here.
找我的话 我就在这里
Mr. Domoto!
堂本先生
Fuwa, I'm sorry.
谱和老弟 很抱歉
I never thought that you would brood over it.
没想到你会这么想不开
You've finally realized?
你终于知道了吗
Because of your selfishness, I was so...
因为你的自私 我是多么地…
It's not like what you think, Fuwa.
并不是这样的 谱和老弟
I retired from playing the piano
我从钢琴界引退
because I noticed that there was something wrong with your tuning.
是因为察觉到你的调音有微妙的不对劲
I knew about your pride,
我考虑到你的自尊心
so I didn't point it out in front of you.
没办法当面指出
Even so, to this day, I still have no intention to work with other tuner.
虽然如此 时至今日我也没有心情和其他调律师合作
That's why I stopped playing the piano.
因此才从钢琴界引退的
No way, I have perfect pitch!
不可能 我拥有绝对音感
Yes, you do.
确实 你拥有绝对音感
But your hearing has declined with age.
但是上了年纪 听觉因而衰退了吧
There were times when you mistuned the piano without noticing it.
偶尔出现过你在无意识下将音律调错的情况
Liar, you lie. A lie, a lie.
骗人 骗人的 骗人的 骗人的
If I know things would become like this, I should have told you the truth.
如果早知这样 我当时应该跟你实话实说的
I am so sorry.
真的对不起
It's already late to apologize.
事到如今道歉也晚了
It's all your fault.
一切都是你的错
No,
不对
if my best friend does the same thing to me,
如果我被挚友做出同样的行为
I would think that maybe she does have a reason
我会想 对方是不是有什么为难的原因
or she cares more about me than herself.
或者觉得 也许朋友比起自己更在替我着想
Why?
要说为什么
Because I trust my friend.
是因为我相信那位朋友
Me too.
我也一样
I can't believe the explosion outside was so serious.
没想到外面居然有这么严重的爆炸
I really had no idea.
一点都没察觉呢
Conan made a great contribution in this case.
柯南好像也活跃了一番呢
I knew it! It's just like what I said.
果然啊 跟我说的一样吧
By the way, I'm surprised Shinichi could understand the code from the recorder sound.
话说回来 新一居然能理解竖笛的暗号呢
After all, the trick of turning notes into English letter
毕竟把音名转换成英文字母的情节
is always seen in detective fictions.
在推理小说里经常出现
Si refers to H in Germany note names.
注：音名就是音高的名称，不同音高的乐音是用C D E F G A B(H)来表示的， 这七个拉丁字母就是乐音的音名。它们一般唱成do re mi fa sol la si，这些名称叫做唱名。 虽然在德国式的音名里si是H
Since he knew that my mom was British.
但他知道我妈妈是英国人
So si refers to B.
si就变成了B
Then he knew that I used English note names.
因此他知道我采用了英国式的音名
I figured he would deduce that instantly.
靠的是他的的瞬间推理
After that, I was counting on his absolute pitch.
之后就是赌一赌他的绝对音感了
I see.
原来如此
Plus, I trust him,
而且 我也相信
as a partner.
作为搭档的他
I thought that Beethoven's fan was the killer.
原本以为那个贝多芬一定是凶手的
Dad is still babbling.
爸爸还在碎碎念啊
However, he still didn't show up.
不过 结果他还是没来啊
That deduction geek.
那个推理小子
Shinichi?
新一？
Whatever, I don't care about him.
随他去了 那种家伙
Let's go, Conan.
我们走吧 柯南
He was here the whole time.
刚才都还一直在的
Listen, the sound.
你听 这个声音
It's a violin.
小提琴啊
It's "Amazing Grace".
是《奇异恩典》啊
No, I mean the way it's performed.
不 我是指这个拉奏手法
The way it was performed?
手法？
Shinichi?
新一？
Wait, Ran!
等等 小兰
Shinichi, Shinichi!
新一 新一
Brother Shinichi already left.
新一哥哥的话 他已经走了哦
Conan.
柯南
He said he had another case.
说是又有案件
Shinichi really came here?
新一果然来了啊
After hearing Miss Reiko singing,
听了怜子小姐的歌后
he said he remembered the thing which happened three years ago.
想起了三年前的往事
Then he played that song with this violin in the academy.
然后用学院里的这把小提琴演奏了刚才的曲子
He said it was for Sister Ran and himself.
他说是献给小兰姐姐和他自己的
Brother Shinichi said that "I have upset Ran".
新一哥哥说“惹小兰不高兴了”
Did you two have a fight?
吵架了吗
It's nothing.
什么事也没有
Even if you have come, I still won't forgive you.
即便来了我也不会原谅你的
You idiot.
笨蛋
He and I always came here in the past.
我以前常和他来这里
This is where we walked on our dates.
这里是我们的约会路线
Really?
是这样啊
On that spring after his accident,
在他意外去世的那个春天
I sang his favorite song
我在和他充满回忆的地方
at the place full of our memories.
唱了他最喜欢的歌
It's "Amazing Grace", right?
就是那首《奇异恩典》吧
Yes.
对
I hate the four men so much at the beginning
我啊 一开始非常痛恨那四个人
and even wanted to kill them.
甚至想杀了他们
But I forgave them at last.
但最后我饶恕了他们
Because "Amazing Grace" is a song about forgiveness.
因为《奇异恩典》是一首宽恕之歌
Well, it's time for me to go.
那 我先走了
Conan, let's sing together next time.
柯南 下次再一起合唱吧
Bye.
走了
See you.
再见
By the way, Miss Ran,
话说回来 小兰姐姐
how did you know that it was Mr. Shinichi who played the violin?
当时你怎么知道是新一哥哥拉的小提琴啊
Because he has a weird habit when he plays the violin.
因为那家伙拉奏时有奇怪的癖好
It's easy to tell.
很容易分辨的
Is that so?
是这样啊
What's this weird habit?
奇怪的癖好到底是什么啊